EMMANUEL ALLAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER && UI/UX DESIGNER



CONTACTS



+(254) 792 922 304



thestrangermax@gmail.com



https://code.maxthestranger.com



maxthestranger

SKILLS

DESIGN

Sketching, Wireframing. UI
 Design, Responsive Design,
 Rapid Prototyping,
 Competitive Analysis,
 Usability Testing, Graphic
 Design

PROGRAMMING

Html, Css, Sass, Tailwind,
 Bootstrap, Javascript, React,
 Ruby, Rest/Graphql, Git, CI/
 CD, Postgres, mysql, mongo

TOOLS

→ Figma, Vs Code, Pivotal tracker, MatterMost, Slack, Meet etc.

EDUCATION

Jan - July, 2021

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

LinkedIn

May, 2020 - Sep, 2020

DESIGN THINKING

PluralSight

May, 2018 - Sep, 2018

ANDELA FELLOWSHIP BOOTCAMP

Andela, Org

May, 2016 - Dec, 2020

COMPUTER SCIENCE

Chuka University

PROFILE

I bring an engineering perspective and creative problem-solving approach to create products and experiences people love to use. Persistence, curiosity, and obsessive attention to detail define me. With a background as a self-taught developer, experience as a UI/UX designer, marketing, and freelancer in product design and development, I am competent in all aspects of the design-develop-test-ship process

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Developer

Savannah Informatics

Jan 2021 - Current

- → Legacy code maintenance ERP system (angular 1.5)
- → Component Design and Testing for Business Tools Team, Slate 360 EDI (angular 1.5)
- → API Documenatation
- → Lots of learning (Pragmatic approach)

Junior Software Developer (Contract)

SoftIQ Technologies

May 2020 - Jan 2021

- → Wireframes, Prototypes and HI-FI Designs for Veve and Gauge applications
- → Developed API endpoints for Veve app in Node(Express)
- → Converted figma designes to a react native mobile app

Web Developer (Freelance)

Upwork

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- → Adapted websites to match changing user preferences and client demands with regular updates.
- → Worked with different clients across the globe to design and develop both mobile and web applications
- → Converted Designs to Web apps and Mobile apps (HTML, CSS, JS, React)

Softare Developer (Intern)

Andela

May 2018 - Sep 2019

- → Assisted internal teams in documenting and testing new applications.
- → Also researched competitor offerings for different projects
- → Took the Andela Bootcamp (Cohort 29) to learn python(flask) and Rest API
- → Lots of learning -- serious learning

SELECTED PROJECTS

Be Well(play store) - An app that gives access to medical services including insuarance cover meta and analytics
Performed Interface Design, Interaction design and information design, Created numerous prototypes of varying fideliity to test assumptions and cencepts. In progress(learning go and DDD)

Veve (play store) - Marketplace for buying Mirra(Khat) products UI/UX Designs (Figma), Mobile Frontend (React Native), Backend Node(express) -- db(postgres)